Guide to the Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute, 2004-2013 UA.26.03.0032
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute Records
2004-2013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute
UA.26.03.0032
2.0 Linear Feet
The Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute is an interdisciplinary center focused on promoting education and action around human rights, which offers an undergraduate certification. The Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute records include materials related to programs and events run by the DHRC, as well as other materials.
Biographical / Historical
"The Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute brings together an interdisciplinary group of scholars, staff and students to promote new understandings of and action on human rights. We engage with issues of race, ethnicity, gender, sexuality, religion, income inequality, the environment, the philosophy and history of human rights, the literature that emerges alongside it, linguistic rights, and artistic responses in our research, teaching, programming and outreach. Our goal is to foster strategies and collaborative, cross-disciplinary and critical thinking about human rights in both local and global contexts. The Center is committed to social justice. In partnership with the FHI, we see the humanities as an essential frame and launch point for inquiry. We develop undergraduate courses and global experiences, sponsor campus-wide events that encourage awareness and activism on human rights and engage in long-term partnerships with community-based organizations."
The DHRC at FHI offers a Human Rights Certificate for undergraduate students, as well as a number of programs including the Rights! Camera! Action! Film Series, RightsWatch, and Bass Connection programs in Human Rights. Since 2009, the DHRC has run the Pauli Murray Project, a series of programs and events for the Durham community.
Source: The Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute website, Mission Statement, https://humanrights.fhi.duke.edu/who-we-are/mission-statement/, accessed 2019 September 05.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in 2019.
Collection Overview
The Duke Human Rights Center at Franklin Humanities Institute records include promotional and other event-related materials, project information, grant materials, and other administrative materials. Included are posters, DVDs, correspondence, and other materials. Most materials are publicly-distributed promotional materials.
Human rights advocacy; Duke Human Rights Center at the Franklin Humanities Institute
- Accession UA2019.0050
  - Promotional Material (Box 1)
  - Pauli Murray Project Promotional Material, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Weaving a Net of Accountability Event Material, April 2010 (Box 1)
  - Duke Human Rights Center Events, Fall 2009-Spring 2010 (Box 1)
  - Duke Human Rights Center Events, Fall 2010-Spring 2011 (Box 1)
  - Duke Human Rights Center Events, No date (Box 1)
  - Northern Ireland Events, 2010 (Box 1)
  - Duke Human Rights Center Events, Fall 2008-Spring 2009 (Box 1)
  - Assorted Flyers, Clippings and Promotional Materials, No date; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Clippings and Promotiona Materials, No date (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Administrative restriction for 25 years from date of creation.
  - Pauli Murray Project Records, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Duke Human Rights Initative, 2004-2006 (Box 1)
  - Pauli Murray Project Materials, 2013; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Human Rights Events Listing (Box 1)
  - Duke Human Rights Center Promotional Material (Box 1)
  - Grants and Donations, no date (Box 1)
  - Steering Committee for Issues of Equity and Staff Training (Box 1)
  - Weaving a Net of Accountability Event Recording, 3 items; DVD
  - Assorted Flyers, Clippings, Posters, and Promotional Materials, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Duke Human Rights Center Poster (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Bass Connections Poster (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Weaving a Net of Accountability Poster (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Duke Human Rights Center Trifolds, 2 items (Oversize-folder 2)
    Posters are trifold.
  - Moral Mathematics Poster (Oversize-folder 1)